TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
쓰레기 불법 투기 금지
DO NOT THROW AWAY TRASH
UNLAWFUL DISPOSAL FORBIDDEN
마스터, 어디? 어디야?
Master, where? Where are you?
메다로트 묘지
Medarot Cemetery
(en: A Night in the Medabot Junkyard)
-어떠냐!
-아직아직!
-How's that?!
-That didn't hurt at all!
가라! 키스터틀!
Go, Kiethturtle!
레이저군요!
Time for my lasers!
-아니야! 돌진해!
-에!
-Wrong! Make a charge!
-What!?
지금이야! 에임 라이플!
Now! Use Aim Rifle!
좋아! 잘 했어, 블루즈독!
Alright! Good job, Bluesdog!
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
괜찮아?
Are you alright?
네.
Yes.
이걸로 카가미야마에게 3연승이네. 강해졌구나, 이와노이.
And that makes three winning strikes against Kagamiyama. You've become better, Iwanoi.
이야, 그 정도에요?
Heh, thank you!
그에 비해, 아주 형편없구나, 너희들!
On contrary to that, you guys are miserable!
페퍼캣.
Peppercat.
네, 두목!
Yes, boss!
스크류즈 로보틀 대결 결과
키쿠히메, 카가미야마, 이와노이
Screws Robattle Results
Kikuhime, Kagamiyama, Iwanoi
요즘 반 녀석들하고의 대전도 계속 지고만 있잖냐.
You're keeping to lose in battles against class people.
대체 어떻게 된 거냐?
What happened to you?
두목, 로보틀이란 뭘까요?
Boss, what is Robattle?
어? 뭐시라?
Huh? What?
메다로트로 배틀하는 걸 말하는 게 당연하잖아?
Isn't it obvious that it means battling using MEdarots?
아니, 그게 아니라, 그...
No, I mean, er...
두목...
Boss...
아까웠어.
We were so close.
죄송합니다, 두목.
I'm sorry, boss.
제가 약해서...
All because I am weak...
틀에 박혀서 말야.
We're being so repetitive.
싸우는 방법 말이야. 레이저 쏘고 나서는 어쩔지.
I'm taking about how we fight. Shoot lasers, and then what?
제, 제 장비는 그렇게 싸우기 위해서...
M- my equipment are made to fight that way.
그렇긴 해도 말이야. 다양하게 해보는 게 재미있을 것 같지 않아? 로보틀하는 건 음, 그러니까...
But you know, it might be more exciting if we try different ways. Don't you think so? Robattling is, well...
그랬습니까. 제가 지시에 잘 따랐으면 이렇게 계속 지고만 있지는 않았겠네요.
I see. If I was responding better to your commands, we wouldn't have keeping to lose.
아니...
Erm.
더 거리를 둬!
Make more distance!
네!
Got it!
그래선 안 돼! 상대의 움직임을 읽어야지!
That won't work! You have to read your enemy's movements!
네!
Alright!
좋아, 코마독! 다시 한번!
Alright, then, Comadog! Try it again!
알았어요멍!
Alright, bark!
그래!
That's it!
-네? 저하고 로보틀하고 싶다고요?
-두목?
-What? You want to have a Robattle against me?
-Boss?
기술을 갈고 닦으려면 실전이 최고잖아? 연습을 도울게.
Trying something out is the best way to become good at! I'll help with your practice.
-도운다고?
-야, 뭔 바람이 불어서 그러냐?
-You're helping?
-Why would you even think about doing that?
아니, 그게...
Well, you know...
세계 제 2의 경지에서 교만하지 않고 다음 세대를 키우기 위해 열렬히 지도하는
I've been moved by the Medarotter's Spirit of Ikki, for passionately guiding the next generation,
잇키의 뜨거운 메다로터 혼에 감동했지.
instead of being arrogant on the 2nd place on the world.
역시 텐료 잇키! 이야, 완전 대통령감이야!
That's the Tenryo Ikki I know! A perfect fit for a president!
이야, 그런 정도야?
Oh, am I that great?
야! 우쭐대다 혼난다!
Hey! Stop getting carried away!
이건 내가 있어서 가능한 로보틀이란거 잊지 마!
I'm the one who's Robattling here!
좋아, 타테야마, 얘한테도 한 수 배울 생각하고 싸워 보자!
Alright, Tateyama, you're getting a lesson from him, too!
어, 네.
Er, sure?
좋아, 잘 됐어.
Great. That went well.
자, 해 보자, 키스터틀!
Let's do this, Kiethturtle!
어, 네!
Er, right!
가볍게 해. 초보자를 상대로 질 리가 없잖아?
Go light on him. Losing to a beginner is impossible!
한번이라도 이기면 기분 나쁜 것도 사라질 거야!
If we win once, that will be enough to make us feel better!
그럼 그걸 위해서 이 로보틀을 해요?
Are you saying that this Robattle is for that?
알겠습니다. 두목을 위해서도 힘낼게요!
I get it. I'll do my best for you, boss, too!
로보틀 파이트!
Robattle fight!
해냈다!
We did it!
이야, 이겼다, 멍!
Yes, we won, bark!
죄, 죄송합니다.
I- I'm sorry.
왜 무리해서 덤벼든 거야!
Why did you hurry to go at!?
이길 거라고 생각했어요.
I thought I would win.
다른 방법으로.
Using another strategy...
이겨야만 했는데...
I had to win.
또 두목에게 수치를.
I failed you again, boss.
-감사합니다!
-이겨서 기뻐, 멍!
-Thank you so much!
-I'm happy that I won, bark!
그렇게 싸워선 못 이겨.
You're never going to win like that.
아니, 초보자를 상대로 진지하게 하면 안 될 거라고 생각해서 말이야...
Well, since we're fighting a beginner, it would have been a bad idea to fight seirously.
너, 요즘들어 계속 똑같이 싸우고 계속 지고만 있잖냐.
Your fights have been similar recently, and you've been keeping to lose.
그, 그럴지도...
You might have a point...
메다로트는 각각 특성이 있어. 그러니까, 다른 방법으로 싸우고 싶으면 메다로트를 바꾸는 수밖에 없어.
Each Medarot has its own properties. That's why you'll have to change your Medarot if you want to try something different.
두목, 그런 거에요? 저하고 싸우는 게 싫어진 거에요?
Is that it, boss? Don't you want to fight with me anymore?
아니야! 나는 너하고 같이 싸우는 게 좋으니까!
That's not it! It's because I like to fight with you!
그래도...
But...
야, 잇키, 말 좀 생각하고 해라.
Hey, Ikki, you went too far.
어, 미안...
Er, I'm sorry.
뭐, 계속 지고 있으니까 뭔 소리를 들어도 어쩔 수 없지.
Well, I guess we'll have to accept that since we're losing all the time.
어서 돌아가야지. 가자, 키스터틀.
We're going back now, Let's go, Kiethturtle.
그거야, 키스터틀, 이와노이한테 지면...
That's it, Kiethturtle, you can't lose to Iwanoi...
두목은 제 능력이 마음에 안 드나 보네요.
I guess you aren't satisfied with my abilities, boss.
키스터틀?
Kiethturtle?
이게 어디야?
Where am I?
지금 나는 이 쓰레기더미하고 마찬가지야.
I'm no different from this mountain of garbage now.
FSL형 팬시롤
FSL Type Fancyroll
누구야?
Who's there?
아, 그게... 너, 여기서 뭐 해?
Er, that's... what are you doing here?
나?
Me?
눈 뜨니까 여기에 있었어.
I was here when I woke up.
이 산더미처럼 쌓인 쓰레기더미,
On a pile of trash,
썩어 문드러진 틴펫들 속에서...
I was among the Tinpets rusting away.
아무리 불러도 마스터는 답하지 않았어.
I've been calling my Master, but no response.
어떻게 된 거야?
What really happened?
나, 버려졌어. 이 쓰레기처럼.
I've been abandoned, just like all the trash here.
그럴 리가!
No way!
마스터하고는 어떤 고난이 있어도 함께였어.
I've been together with my Master, no matter what was going on.
항상 함께일 거라고 믿었어.
I believed that we will be together forever.
그런데...
But...
너도 그렇게 된 거지?
Same happened to you, right?
아, 그게, 나는...
Well, for me...
나는 혼자였어. 그래도 이제 외롭지 않아.
I was alone all along. But not anymore...
친구가 생겼으니.
...since that I have a friend now.
자신을 잃고 마스터한테서 달아났다고는 말하지 못하겠어.
I can't tell her that I ran away because I had no confidence in myself.
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
키스터틀! 답해!
Kiethturtle! Respond!
젠장, 전파가 안 닿나 봐!
Damn, the radio isn't strong enough!
키스터틀! 답해!
Kiethturtle! say something!
두목...
Boss...
인간의 목소리가 나오는군!
I hear human voice!
너에게서 인간 목소리가!
I hear human from you!
갑자기 왜 그래!?
Why did you do that!?
괘, 괜찮아?
A- are you alright?
인간은...
Humans...
싫어!
I abhor them!
야, 잇키.
Hey, Ikki.
일어나, 야!
Wake up! Hey!
-대체 왜 그래.
-저거.
-Why did you wake me up?
-That.
야! 그만 좀 자!
Hey! Stop falling asleep!
잇키, 네 탓이야!
Ikki, it's all your fault!
뭐야, 밤중에 뜬금없이!
What is it, out of the blue!?
없어! 키스터틀이!
I can't find my Kiethturtle!
어?
What?
뭔 일이야? 이런 밤중에.
What's wrong? It's deep in night.
네, 아이들은 제가 책임지고 데려다 주겠습니다.
Yes, I'll take care of the children.
이제 됐어. 양해는 구했으니.
You're all good, since I got the permissions.
미안해요. 이렇게 늦어서는 저희끼리만으로는 못 찾으니까...
I'm sorry, but we couldn't find him by ourselves.
괜찮아. 너희 기분은 잘 알아.
It's alright. I understand you guys.
저, 더 키스터틀하고 로보틀을 하고 싶었어요.
I wanted to do more Robattles with Kiethturtle.
정해진 능력만으로 싸우는 게 아니라, 아무도 해본 적 없는 전법을 써 보고...
I don't want to fight only using abilities that I know, but instead, I'd like to try something completely new.
그래, 그래. 천편일률적인 명령만 해서는 나도 지루하고 말야.
Yeah, agreed. Doing same thing all over would make even me bored.
내가 괜한 소리를 해서...
I shouldn't have said that.
단서는 있니?
Any clues?
보였던 건 이것뿐이에요.
This is all I saw.
오래된 여관 같구나.
It looks like an old inn.
이 마을에 그런 게 있었나...
I don't recall seeing that in this city...
음양 마을 지도에서 찾아보자.
Let's find it on the Ginjou map.
그래, 저거야!
That's it!
재개발 지구?
Reconstruction site?
여기 역이 생기기 전에는 번화했던 곳 같은데, 지금은 별로 사람이 살고 있지 않나 봐.
It seems that it was a lively city before a station was made, but I guess it's not anymore.
유령 도시구나.
It's a ghost town.
키스터틀 놈, 이런 곳에 혼자...
Kiethturtle came all the way here by himself...
저기야.
There's the place.
Medarot Damashii - Subtitles by Subdiver
쓰레기 불법 투기 금지
DO NOT THROW AWAY TRASH
UNLAWFUL DISPOSAL FORBIDDEN
와, 끔찍하다.
This is bad.
봐봐.
Take a look.
마을이 없는 것 같아.
No city there.
-메다롯치로 불러 봐.
-어.
-Try calling him with your Medarotch.
-Right.
키스터틀, 어디야?
Kiethturtle, where are you?
어이, 잇키. 뭐야, 저건?
Hey, Ikki, what's that?
뭐, 뭐야?
W- what's going on?
저거...
That's...
모, 모두 어서 차에 타!
E- everyone, to the truck!
젠장! 누구야!
Dammit! Who was that!?
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
왜 그래, 키스터틀!?
What's wrong, Kiethturtle!?
저건 팬시롤!
That's Fancyroll!
오래된 타입의 메다로트야. 이미 수년전에 생산이 중단됐어.
That's an old type Medarot. It's not manufactured since years ago.
저 놈 마스터는 어디 있는 거야?
Where is her Master?
마스터 따위 없어!
I don't have a Master!
메타비!
Metabee!
괘, 괜찮아.
I- I'm fine.
이제 어째, 잇키?
What should we do now, Ikki?
어쩌냐니!
What, you don't know?
대체 왜?
W- why?
메다로트가 인간을 습격하다니 있으면 안 되는 일이야!
Medarots should not attack humans!
인간 따위 싫어!
I abhor humans!
이거 어떻게 된 거야!?
What's going on here!?
나는 버려졌다. 몇년을 함깨 지내온 마스터에게!
I am abandoned, by my Master who I spent time for years!
거짓말이야! 메다로터가 메다로트를 버리는 일이 있을 리가 없어!
You're lying! There's no way Medarotter would abandon a Medarot!
어디 보시라.
Take a look.
인간은 자신 좋을 대로 무언가를 좋아하다가도 필요 없어지면 버리고 만다.
While humans may love something when they want to, they will abandon when it becomes useless.
함께 나눈 기억도 전부.
That includes all the memory they shared.
나는 그런 인간을 용서할 수 없다!
I cannot forgive such humans!
그만해! 제발 그만둬, 키스터틀!
Stop! Please stop, Kiethturtle!
나에 씨! 카가미야마!
Ms. Nae! Kagamiyama!
메타비, 여기는 우리끼리 어떻게 할 수밖에 없어!
Metabee, you know that we're the only hope, right!?
그래! 어디 봐라, 니들 따위 조금도 안 무서워!
Of course! You'll soon find out that we're not scared at al!
해 보자! 퓨저, 블래스터, 일제 사격!
Let's do this! Fuser and Blaster, fire at once!
흥, 달아났겠다!
Hmph, you may have made your way out!
멀리 못 갈 테다.
...for now.
틀렸어! 벌써 저 앞까지 왔잖아!?
We're doomed! They're already here!
대체 왜야. 왜 키스터틀은 날 노리는 거야?
Why is it? Why is Kiethturtle after me?
팬시롤의 머리 부분에 버그 공격의 능력이 있어. 분명 그걸 이용해서 키스터틀을 조종하는 것일 테야.
Fancyroll's head part has bug attack ability. She's probably using that to control over Kiethturtle.
그럼 저 틴펫도 죄다?
Does that include all those Tinpets?
그래. 메달이 없으면 그냥 인형일 뿐. 제어 시스템이 살아 있으면...
Yes. Without medals, they're dolls; nothing else. If their control systems are active...
최고의 병기가 돼.
...they become dreadful weapons.
나, 모르겠어. 메다로트하고 메다로터가 헤어지다니! 그러니까, 잇키하고 내가 헤어지는 일이 있을 리가 없잖아!
I don't get it. How can a Medarot and a Medarotter separate? I mean, there's no way that Ikki and I set apart!
당연하지!
Of course not!
나하고 키스터틀도!
Kiethturtle and me too!
아니야. 있어.
Wrong. They do.
믿고 싶지 않겠지만, 어떻게 해도 헤어져야만 하는 때가.
Nobody wants to believe it, but sometimes they have to part.
어른이 되면 대부분의 사람들이 메다로트에서 손을 떼고 말아. 아마 그 팬시롤네 마스터도.
When people become adults, they let go of Medarot. Fancyroll's Master had to do so too, probably.
저런...
No way...
싫어! 난 절대 로보틀을 관두지 않을 거야!
That can't happen! I will never stop doing Robattling!
그래, 잇키 군이라면.
Right, you won't.
그래도 인간은 성장해. 언제나 이러고만 있을 수는 없어.
Humans grow nonetheless. You can't stay like that forever.
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
뭐, 뭐야, 저거!
W- what's that!?
뱀이냐!
A snake!?
더는 갈 곳이 없으리!
No more slipping away!
-고민하고 있을 때가 아니야! 잇키!
-어, 여기서 빠져나가지 못하면 같이 살고 싶어도 못 해!
-Worry later, Ikki!
-Yeah, if we can't make it out, we won't be together anymore!
-메타비!
-어!
-Metabee!
-Right!
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
가라!
Go!
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
카가미야마!
Kagamiyama!
부탁이야! 정신 차려줘!
Please! Wake up!
카가미야마 군!
Kagamiyama!
나에 씨!
Ms. Nae!
메타비! 너라도 달아나!
Metabee! At least you can run away!
잇키!
Everyone!
싫어. 싫어. 인간 따위 싫어!
I hate them. I despise them. I loathe humans!
그만해! 제발 그만!
Stop! Please stop!
저 빛을 막아야 해.
You have to block that light.
근데 어떻게?
But how?
이래선 끝이 없어!
There's no end to this!
그래!
Right!
메타비! 레클리스 모드로! 너라면 이걸 오를 수 있을 거야!
Metabee! To Reckless Mode! You can climb this up!
그랬지!
Right!
가라, 메타비!
Go for it, Metabee!
인간 모습의 너희들도 가증스럽다.
You look like humans, and that alone is worthy of my hatred.
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
난 네가 싫어진 게 아니야!
I never hated you!
너하고 어떻게 도와 싸울지, 더욱더 같이 생각해 나가고 싶었어!
Instead, I always wanted to help each other by thinking together!
지면 아무렴 어때! 너하고 로보틀을 할 수만 있다면!
What if you lose, as long as we can do Robattles together?
무엇보다도 난...
And I...
네가...
like you...
정말 좋으니까!
...very much!
팬시롤 좋아!
Fancyroll, I like you!
싫어! 정말 싫어!
I hate this! I hate everything!
정말 좋아, 팬시롤!
I like you so much, Fancyroll!
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
마스터...
Master...
키스터틀!
Kiethturtle!
저, 달아났는데...
I have run away...
괜찮아! 다 괜찮아!
It's alright! Don't mention it!
-야, 잇키!
-해냈어, 메타비!
-Hey, Ikki!
-You made it, Metabee!
나에 씨, 내 활약 쭉 봤지!?
Ms. Nae, did you enjoy all my awesome work!?
메타비도 참.
Oh, Metabee.
-시, 싫어.
-어?
-I... I still hate...
-What the?
인간 따위...
Damned humans...
-망할!
-잠시.
-Damn you!
-Stop.
네 메모리 뱅크에서...
I've received data...
데이터가 흘러왔어.
...from your memory bank.
네 마스터가 정말 좋았나 봐.
I see you liked your master so much.
그렇지만 우리 메다로트는 마스터가 로보틀을 관두면 사명도 끝나.
But the mission of us Medarots ends when the Masters quit Robattling.
분명 어떻게 못 할 일이 있었을 거야.
I guess that she went through something unavoidable.
팬시롤, 고마워.
Fancyroll, thank you.
마스터...
Master...
인간을 증오해서는 마스터하고의 기억을 네 자신이 부수는 거야.
By hating humans, you're destroy all the good memories with your Master.
그건 네가 그렇게 좋아하던 마스터의 마음마저 상처입히는 일이라고 생각해.
I think that doing so also destroys the feelings of your Master that you liked with all your heart.
마스터의 마음...
Master's feelings...
키스터틀...
Kiethturtle...
왜 눈을 뜬 거야.
Why did you have to wake up?
눈을 뜨지만 않았다면 이런 기억을 떠올릴 필요도 없었는데.
If you didn't see through, I wouldn't have to be reminded of these memories.
내 기억, 전부 지워 줘.
All my memories... Erase them.
영원히...
Let me rest...
재워 줘.
...forever.
메다로트 사의 재활용 공장에도 아주 가끔 초기화되지 않은 메달이 들어있는 채로 보내지는 메다로트가 있어.
Sometimes, Medarots are sent to Medarot Company's recycling factory with a medal that hasn't been reset.
새로운 마스터를 찾고 있습니다
Looking for new masters
그이도 분명 뭔가 잘못해서 거기에 버리고 말았던 거야.
Her Master must have made a mistake, leaving her there.
저, 이 아이 괜찮아요?
Excuse me... can I adopt her?
소중히 여겨 줘.
Treat her as preciously as you can.
네!
Right!
있잖아, 잇키, 우리도 언젠간...
Hey, Ikki. Will we have to eventually...
바보야. 언젠가고 자시고, 내게 제일 소중한 건 너하고 만난 거야.
Stupid. Eventually or not, encountering you is the most precious memory to me.
더욱더 다양한 걸 하고 싶어. 메타비하고.
I want to do more exciting things... with you, Metabee.
어, 나도야, 잇키!
Yeah, me too, Ikki!
가자, 메타비!
Let's go, Metabee!
좋아!
Yeah!
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
메다로트 사 주최 음양 마을 로보틀 대회
Medarot Company presents Ginjou City Robattle Contest
마을 내 로보틀 대회에서 결승전까지 연승한 잇키와 메타비.
Ikki and Metabee made their way through to the final match in a Robattle contest in city.
대전 상대는 놀랍게도 유니트리스를 쓰는 긴카이였다.
Their opponent was, surprisingly, Ginkai with Unitrix.
거기에 난입한 건 블로소메일을 쓰는 코쿠류였다.
The one to intrude into the match was Kokuryu with Blossomail.
블로소메일의 엄니가 메타비를 끌어당긴다.
Blossomail's fangs are drawing Metabee towards her.
메타비, 위기!
Metabee's in a pinch!
그 때, 코쿠류에게 맞선 건 누구?
At that moment, someone stood against Kokuryu!
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 일어나라! 긴카이
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Stand Up! Ginkai
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!